Okay. So, saints,
I have been muted that whole time,
[laughter]
so I get to say all that again. Happy
Sabbath, happy new year. Welcome to
Living Mana's uh prayer and praise time.
What a way to start the year off, right?
I mean, in that in that example of what
our year is going to be like, it is
through much prayer and through much
persevering that we gonna make it, but
we're going to make it. You know, I was
just telling the ladies there in
Florida, look.
He might shut us up for a minute, but he
can't shut us down. He might shut us
down for a minute, but he can't shut us
up. Thank God that it's Sabbath all day.
Thank you for giving me that call just
now, pastor, letting me know I was on
mute. I didn't even know. I mean, we're
all over the place trying to see what's
going on. But you know that teaches us
we don't want to be
rigid. We don't want to be dogmatic. We
want to be open-minded. And we want to
be ready to follow the leading of the
Holy Spirit. I see you all there in the
chat. Some of y'all praying with me.
Some of y'all amen. Some of y'all
laughing. That's all right. We got to be
able to laugh through. We got to have
the joy of the Lord as we persevere
through some of these trials. And as I
was saying, saints, love all of you all.
I see you there. Praise God. It is an
honor to be able to serve you in this
capacity. And as you heard that
introduction, that music and and the
voice over, someone was asking who that
voiceover is. I think it's our beloved
sister Annette. It sounds like her. It
says that you're not alone. And you're
not alone in your struggle. If you're
watching today and you've tuned in and
you're getting ready to hear this
incredible word from the Lord today, if
you tuned in earlier and got some of
your questions answered during the
question and answering uh segment of the
Sabbath school, which was really
beautiful, by the way, we got a chance
to see Tiger. I know some of you were
excited about that. I was I was Tiger
came in and right on time, too, because
we had questions about our animals and
stuff. But anyway, it appears that I am
alone today. uh and and and there's an
object lesson even in that. For some of
you, you seem like you're alone in your
struggle and your trial. You are not.
And if you were with us at the beginning
of the service, first lady announced
that um we have some powerful women of
of prayer from living mana who are
together in Florida in Orlando at the
GYC. Ammer's there, she's there with
Jackie, she's there with sister Denise,
and she's there with sister Charene.
We'll be introducing them in just a
minute, but uh before they come up, I
just wanted to say we love y'all and
thank God for you. Pray that your new
year would be a blessed new year. Psalm
65:1 says, "He crowneth the year with
goodness and his paths drop with fatness
and so or fatness or abundance." And so
we want to pray that here at the
beginning of the new year, you will hook
up with God in such a way. Our covenant
keeping God. Believe him, trust him,
press into him, lean upon him. We've
never come this way before, but he has
seen this. And nothing that will happen
in this year, nothing that will happen
in your life around your life, nothing
you will hear or experience or feel will
catch him by surprise. God's come this
way before and he's made provision for
you and for me. And so, saints, uh, we
just want to reach out to you and say we
love you. Let us serve you this year.
Let us be the hands and feet of Jesus in
your life. and also keep us in prayer
that we do this thing together. We are
family and and definitely we love all of
y'all. Happy Sabbath. Happy Sabbath. I
see you in the chat. Everybody
seeing y'all, we love y'all. And uh
listen, it's it's the love that we get
from you and it is the the lives that we
get a chance to impact. It's the reason
why we do what we do. Amen. And so look,
really I the ladies will tell you I told
them before we came on I says watch as
soon as that prayer segment gets ready
to come on the enemy going to try to
shut this thing down. And sure they'll
tell you when they come on that's
exactly what happened. That's all right.
We're not discouraged. We're not in
despair. We're not without hope. You
know we know that we're we're a fighting
people. Amen. We we fight the good fight
of faith. We stand on the word of the
living God. We don't walk by sight. We
walk by faith and we hold on and we
endure. Amen. And so now let us give God
some praise as these beautiful
handmaidaidens, beautiful sisters come
on and and do some testifying and talk
about the goodness of God here at the
beginning of the year. He said he
crowned the year with goodness, right?
So I want to invite Sister Amra and
Sister Denise and Sister Jackie and
Sister Shaun to come on. And uh there
they go. Hallelujah. Look at them.
Hey sisters, y'all ain't muted. Are you
Are you muted?
>> Can you hear us? Can you hear us?
>> Yes, we hear you. Praise God for y'all.
>> Amen.
>> I want to say happy new year, Living Man
of Family. It's such a blessing to be
here with my sisters. I get to meet um
fantastic women of God in person for the
first time and it just warms my heart.
As you can hear, I unfortunately came
down with laryngitis.
Perry's dream come true finally.
I can't talk
but I'm gonna keep it short. But um
we're going to each picture and um you
know Jackie Sha want to share a little
something and Denise has been so
gracious to read the praise report for
me. So you guys do not scream to hear
what I what I'm trying to read. So
again, happy new year. Such a blessing
to be here with you all.
>> Oh, praise God. Praise God. Happy new
year church family.
>> I am so glad that I came to this event.
Um it was a very intimate
uh moment for me. Praise God. And what
made it so intimate and special is that
I ran into Pastor Mark Finley. He
actually did five sessions in last days.
And and why was this so special uh for
me?
Prior to coming into the Adventist
space, I ran across uh Pastor Mark
Finley and Sean Boostra on a broadcast
channel called TVN, which is Trinity
Broad uh broadcasting network, which is
a uh a non-adventic channel. I ran
across them and heard the message and I
loved it. I just I mean I just they just
drew my heart. And thereafter, I
continued to watch, continue to watch,
continue to watch it. Even if I went to
church that Sunday, I uh I recorded it.
And as soon as I came home, I watched
it. Well, fast and this was like the
early 2000s. We Danny and I came into
the Adventist faith in 2005.
And this was before that time. So after
we came into the Adventist faith, I had
no idea that that p that pastor Mark
Finley and Sean Busher was Saturday
Adventist and so happened they were at
an event that was being hosted by the
conference that I was in and I look
for
[laughter]
God. But you know what made that so
special for me? And this is why it's so
intimate.
I had the opportunity to share this with
him and I told Danny, I said, "If I ever
run into Pastor Mark or Sean Booster, I
have to let them know that they were
part a very intimate part of my journey
into Adventism." And they didn't even
realize it. And I had the privilege and
opportunity to do that. And so, I just
want to praise God. It was a very
intimate moment for me, a special
moment.
>> Amen. And
gosh, it made me think,
God is always at work. He was always at
work in my life and in yours, whether we
know it or not. Little did I know,
little did I know, God, even then, God
was prepping me. He was preparing me to
change the things. And I praised. And
when the opportunity avail itself to my
husband and I, I just want to praise God
that he gave me the strength and courage
to make that change. And that's when we
we we we became Adventists. And I tell
you today, I mean, I think was it was I
think it was Wednesday when I had a
chance to uh to give him my testimony,
but it was also a special testimony for
me because it was a reminder that my God
is always at work in my life even when
we don't know him. But praise God. And
since we have come into this faith, boy,
we have not regretted it. Not one
moment. And it was like a stealing time
for me, right? still this is where
you're supposed to be. This is where you
need to be. And it was a reminder how
God has led us in the past and he will
continue to lead us in the future.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen. Yes.
So, I'm having a wonderful time
to see what my amazing sister,
but it's like we have known each other.
It was just like it was just like
seamless. It was like, oh no, it was
everything just is the same but online.
It's like the same people who do the
same stuff. I mean we're rooming, but I
mean like it's it's so amazing.
I love it.
>> [laughter]
>> But I've had the opportunity
all over the world background.
But last year there were 4800
people at the Ohio 2024
life. This year there were over 7,000
people from all over the world. And I
say that all over the world and there
are people ages there. I mean a lot of
people our age a lot of people I mean
all babies up to
their amazing
>> and when I say that even with everything
that's happening today we have more God
increased and people to get here they
were able to fellowship together and
so I pray that you
Great.
Everybody
love that. We just love that that Christ
centered energy that they are young
people who people of all ages coming
together and worshiping together and
loving Christ
together as one. And so I hope that
bring our family.
>> But I mean,
so that
participates.
So all I can say is that
lady
[laughter]
I don't know next year but we are
actually put it on our website
in my networking
for
so I'm
gonna give us but
is a report
seminar.
[laughter]
>> Amen. Amen. Uh praise reports. Uh we've
heard some amazing praise reports so far
and I want to I have the pleasure of
reading the praise report from our
church family. Our first praise report
comes from Sister Takara Bumpers. Happy
New Year, Sister Takara. Uh and it reads
from my uncle. This just happened. My
cousin is in need of a miracle
from Uncle Anthony. Original prayer
request. Everyone please pray for
Anthony. He was in a car accident and
has been flown to UK hospital in
Lexington. His neck has been separated
from his spine
and he needs emergency surgery. Please
pray for my little person Anthony
Jenkins. He just had a brand new baby
and his wife. He was in the accident.
And this is the police report.
My name is wonderful
mighty God,
wonderful comfort, prince of
everlasting father.
I cried unto the Lord and he heard my
cry and he touched Anthony.
They are saying no surgery is needed.
Yes.
>> And he may go home today.
He will need physical therapy,
but no real damage was done.
No head trauma.
Nothing ruptured.
God turned it around.
What the devil meant for evil,
God made
his good.
Thank God. Allelujah. Allelujah.
Allelujah.
Second prayer of course from Francis
Brandt. Happy new year, Sister Francis.
Please remember my husband Nigel in
prayer.
He was rushed to the hospital last night
because he was not responsive.
His sugar was extremely low.
They were able to get the sugar level
back, but he's still very lethargic and
slow in giving proper answers.
He's been admitted to the hospital.
Please continue to lift in lifting him
up in prayer as they are concerned
he may be having a neurological
incident.
Here come the praise report.
I want to give God all the honor, glory,
and praise.
Thank you for all your prayers and
support.
My husband Nigel is being released from
the hospital tomorrow at 200 p.m.
>> to return back to the rehabilitation
center. And again,
they gain back his strength.
>> And I got capital letters, hallelujah,
too. Hallelujah. Hallelujah.
Hallelujah. And I got a capital letter
of glory. Amen.
God enabled to do exceedingly abundantly
beyond all that we can think or even
imagine.
Blessed be the name forever more. Amen.
Yes, Sister Princess. Yes, Sister
Princess.
Sister, happy new year, Sister Joanne.
Next last report is from Sister Joanne
Stevens, our wonderful sister from
Trinidad and Tobago.
I have to pray. I have to praise God.
Oh, I can just hear it. I have to praise
God. [laughter]
But I am still alive and well.
On Boxing Day, and for anybody who
doesn't know, Americans, everybody else
celebrates Boxing Day the day after
Christmas. So on Boxing Day, my brother,
cousin, and I were coming back home from
a family get together.
When we narrowly
escaped causing an act,
one of my brothers got his license for
the first time at age 55
and swears
he's a driving god. [laughter]
Okay, I swear he's a driving god.
>> Just blissfully.
across the intersection.
As he was crossing one car,
coming up the opposite direction while
he slide in between two cars,
flowing down our direction
and sp himself between them.
Even as another was about to overtake
others, he fitted
between.
Of course, we saw our night life
and she laughed. And if you haven't
heard Mr. Joanne laugh, it's an amazing
laugh. But I have to thank God that
before we drove off and I insisted that
we pause and prayed for protection on
the road.
Our God is our constant shield and
protector.
Praise him. So while all that was going
on, God just had them had them nestled
right there.
Praise God. And that concludes the proof
report.
Back to brother Terry.
>> Don't forget to put your prayers in
because without pray without prayers
there's no praise.
All
right,
That's it.
We're an anchor [singing]
for those
who are hurting.
And we're a harbor [singing] for those
who are lost.
And sometimes [singing] it's [music] not
always
easy
bearing
Calary [singing]
cross.
And we've been ridiculed by those
[singing]
who don't know him
and even mocked [music] by those who
don't believe. [singing]
[music] But still, I love standing up
for my [music] Jesus
after all [singing]
that he's done for me.
That's why I am not ashamed [music]
of the gospel, [singing]
the gospel [music]
of Jesus [singing]
Christ.
>> [music]
>> And that's why I am not afraid
[music] to be counted.
But I'm willing to give my life.
You see, I'm ready to be all he
[singing] wants me [music] to be.
I'll give up the
for the [singing] right.
No, I am not ashamed
of the gospel.
No,
I am not ashamed
of the gospel
of [music] Jesus.
[singing]
For every moment his hand has had mercy.
For all the love [singing] that he shown
[music] in my life.
A simple thanks. Couldn't say how I'm
[singing] feeling.
[music]
I get tears in my eyes.
But as for me, [singing and music]
I'm going to keep on believing.
Yes, I am in the one who's been so
faithful to me. [music]
And I'm not out to please this [music]
whole world [singing] around me. Cuz
I've got my mind on
>> [singing]
>> eternity.
And that's why I am not
[music and singing] ashamed of the
gospel.
Oh, the gospel of [singing] Jesus
[music]
Christ.
And that's why I am not [singing] afraid
to be counted.
But I'm willing to give my
life.
See, I'm ready to be all He wants me to
be.
I'll give up the
for the ride.
No, I am not ashamed [music and singing]
of this gospel.
No, no. I am not ashamed of the gospel
[music and singing]
of Jesus
Christ.
[singing and music]
To some, he's just a name, but to me
he's my everything. [music] That's why I
am not ashamed
of the gospel.
No. [music] Know I am not ashamed of the
gospel
cuz I got too much behind me to let this
world guide me. [music]
You see to some he's just a name but to
me
he's my everything [music] and that's
why I am not ashamed of the gospel.
No, [singing] no. I am not ashamed of
the gospel. [music]
No, no. I am not ashamed of the gospel
[music]
of Jesus [singing]
Christ.
Oh,
[singing]
[music]
thank you very much.
In the skilled hands of a potter, clay
takes a remarkable transformation.
[music]
It is a humble substance, unassuming and
formless. Yet, in the hands of the
potter, it becomes a medium of
incredible potential.
With each touch, the potter breathes
[music] life into the clay, coaxing it
into shapes and forms that were
previously unimaginable.
The potter's [music] hands possess a
unique understanding of the clay. They
have a profound sense of touch, able to
[music] discern its resilience and
responsiveness. With patience and
precision, the potter begins to [music]
shape the clay, molding it into vessels
of beauty and functionality. There is an
artistry [music] in this process, a
dance between the potter and the clay.
With each stroke and twist, [music] the
potter guides the clay, bringing forth
its hidden possibilities. The clay
yields to the potter's touch, trusting
in the vision and expertise [music] that
resides within those hands.
But the journey of clay [music] in the
potter's hands is not without
challenges.
There are moments of pressure and
[music] stretching as the potter seeks
to refine and strengthen the clay. In
these [music] moments the clay may
resist, yet it is in these trials the
true character emerges as imperfections
are [music] smothered away and the clay
becomes resilient.
It is through the work of the [music]
Holy Spirit and interactions we
encounter that we are formed. Like clay,
we must be pliable and open, willing to
yield to the hands of the great potter.
Life's challenges, though [music]
daunting, are opportunities for growth.
The pressures and stretches we endure
shape our character and strengthen our
spirit. Just as the potter refineses the
clay, so too does adversity refine us,
[music] chiseling away our rough edges
and revealing the true essence God
intended for us.
The great potter has crafted us with
intention and parting us with unique
talents and gifts. It is our
responsibility to embrace the shaping
process, [music] to trust in the wisdom
of the potter's hands.
So let us be clay in the potter's hands,
yielding and open to transformation. Let
us trust in the artistry of the potter,
knowing [music] that through his touch,
we can become vessels of beauty and
significance. And as [music] we embrace
this process, may we inspire others to
recognize the joy that is in
surrendering to the hands of the divine
potter.
>> [music]
>> Amen. Church family. Um I want to wish
you all a happy Sabbath. And uh as we
prepare to get into the word of God
today, uh it is my prayer that uh as we
start this new year, this message
will uh touch you
in a very special way. Um
and that it'll kind of set the tone for
how you walk uh through this year.
and how we how we prepare for the second
coming of Christ. And so with that guys,
we're going to go ahead and have a word
of prayer. And as usual, I'm going to
ask you to put a one in the chat if you
are ready for some living mana. Um
please once again, we had some more
technical issues with the broadcast
link. So a new link is up. Um let people
know that the link is up. Please share
the link. If you have not yet subscribed
to our Living Mana YouTube channel,
please go ahead and do so. Um, today is
a day of technical difficulties and uh
I'm probably going to be preaching
without slides today. So, I just really
need y'all to focus and lock in.
And um let's uh let's go ahead and pray
and ask the Lord to bless this food as
we prepare to eat.
Heavenly Father, [clears throat]
we ask Lord today in a special way that
you would please speak to your people,
Lord. Lord, you know that I'm sick. You
know that I have a cold. You know that
my voice um is struggling today, Lord.
So, please just um walk with us through
this message, Lord. And um Lord, may the
words that are spoken be uplifting and
glorifying to you. Thank you, Lord.
for your amazing grace
in Jesus name we pray. Amen.
So um I want to begin guys uh with uh
painting a scene for you
um in the book of Luke. In the book of
Luke, chapter 22,
uh Jesus has uh just been surrounded by
the Roman guards
and he's about to be taken.
And it's a chaotic scene. It's a chaotic
scene. In fact, everything we're about
to read
um from this
point of Christ being captured
really speaks to to um
the the darkness of sin.
And uh I want to read to you Luke 22
verse uh verse 53.
So Jesus says, "When I was daily with
you in the temple, you stretched forth
no hands against me, but this is your
hour and the power of darkness."
So Jesus launches into this what is
about to be his final hours, his final
days on this earth. And he calls this
time period the power
and the hour of darkness. This is
significant.
Uh just a little bit earlier Jesus had
spoken to his disciples saying to them
in John 14:30 he said hereafter will I
not talk much with you for the prince of
this world cometh and has nothing in me.
He knew [clears throat]
what was coming ahead for his people for
himself and for his disciples.
He knew
the crisis that lay ahead.
And and as we unlock this scene, there's
something I want to bring your attention
to you need to pay very close attention
to. In Matthew chapter 26 and verse 20,
the Bible says, "And when the evening
was come,
he sat down with the 12." And so this is
this is the beginning of this time of
trouble. This is the beginning of
Jesus's moment of crisis. And it begins
with this phrase. It was at evening that
he sat down with the 12. He's about to
to break bread with the disciples. He's
about to to do what is called that last
supper.
And and the Bible tells us that it is as
the the sun is going down.
And this is significant you guys because
the sun going down
not only is happening in a literal sense
but there is a darkness that is coming
upon
upon this earth at this time period that
is unlike anything that the world has
ever experienced.
It says it was as at evening that that
that he sat down with the 12 and and
then we know the story that Judas uh uh
is going to betray Jesus and and in John
13:30 the Bible says he then having
received the soop went immediately out
and then it says again as if to
emphasize the point and it was night
and it was night that is significant
it was night.
It was
dark. The darkness of sin was settling
upon the earth.
In Matthew chapter 26, Jesus is now in
the garden of Gethsemane. And the Bible
says in verse 36, Matthew chapter
26:36-3
to39, the Bible says here, "Then cometh
Jesus with them into a place called
Gethsemane, and saith unto his
disciples, sit ye here while I go and
pray yonder.
And he took Peter with him and the two
sons of Zebedee,
and began to be sorrowful and very
heavy.
Then saith you unto them, My soul is
exceeding sorrowful, even unto death.
carry ye here and watch with me. And he
went in a little further and fell on his
face and prayed, saying, Father, if it
be possible, let this cup pass from me.
Nevertheless, not as I will, but as thou
will. I want you to sense the darkness
that is coming over Jesus. So, we see
that that that at the at the last
supper, it was evening. We see that
Judas when he went out to betray Jesus,
it was night. We now see Jesus in the
garden of Gethsemane. He's praying and
this darkness is coming over his soul.
And then we see the words where Jesus as
the Roman soldiers uh uh take hold of
him, he says, "This is your hour and the
power of darkness." And what ensues,
beloved, is is simple.
It is simple. Pure wickedness, pure
darkness, pure chaos, if I may use that
word. In Matthew 27:32, they came out.
They found a man ofSirene, Simon by
name. He him compelled to bear to bear
his cross. And when they were coming to
the place called Golgoth, that is to
say, the place of a skull, they gave him
vinegar to drink, mingled with Gaul. And
when he had tasted thereof, he would not
drink. And they crucified him and parted
his garments, casting lots, that it
might be fulfilled which was spoken by
the prophet. They parted my garments
among them, and upon my vestures they
did cast lots. And sitting down, they
watched him there, and set up over his
head this his accusation written, "This
is Jesus, the King of the Jews."
Then were the two thieves crucified with
him, one on the right hand and the other
on the left.
And they pass they that passed by
reviled him, wagging their heads, and
saying, Thou that destroyth the temple,
buildeth it in three days, save thyself,
if thou be the son of God,
come down from the cross.
And we know how the story goes.
We see the pure chaos that unfolds
as Jesus is being beaten,
mocked,
bruised,
and crucified.
Then another interesting verse in Luke
23:44, the Bible says, "And it was about
the sixth hour, and there was a darkness
all over the earth until the 9th hour.
And the sun was darkened, and the veil
of the temple was rent in the midst."
And when Jesus had cried with a loud
voice, he saidf, "Father, into thy hands
I commend my spirit." And having said
thus, he gave up the ghost.
What I want you guys to focus on is the
absolute
darkness. Follow me carefully.
The absolute darkness
that the earth is experiencing.
[cough]
[clears throat]
In Amos chapter 8:9,
the Bible prophesied this when it said,
"It shall come to pass in that day, say
the Lord, that I will cause the sun to
go down at noon, and I will darken the
earth in the clear day." This this
crucifixion of Christ,
it is clear day
and yet the sun
is darkened.
What I want you to understand beloved is
that this signifies the darkest time of
earth's history.
All the darkness of sin and Satan
we can say has been
has been condensed into this one period
of time where mankind
is literally putting to death
their creator
and then Jesus
dies.
The Bible says in Psalm 88:6, "Thou hast
laid me in the lowest pit in darkness
in the deeps." I want you to understand
how death, beloved, is like darkness.
Death is there is it is a nothingness.
It is the deepest darkness that there
is.
The Bible says in Matthew 27:57
that that when Jesus dies
[clears throat]
that he is put into a tomb. Matthew
27:58 he went to Pilate um this is
Joseph of Arythea went to Pilate begged
the body of Jesus then Pilate commanded
the body to be delivered and g and
Joseph when he had taken the body he
wrapped it in a clean linen cloth and
laid it in his own tomb which he had
hewed out in the rock and he rolled a
great stone to the door of the sepiler
and departed. So I want you to
understand what is happening here.
Jesus is now locked in a tomb.
There is no light in that tomb.
It is a place of utter darkness.
It is a place of utter darkness. It is a
place that is symbolic of emptiness.
Lamentations.
Lamentations 3:6. He set me in the dark
place like those who have been long
dead. Job 10 20 21 and 22. Before I go,
whence I shall not return, even to the
land of darkness and the shadow of
death, a land of darkness, of darkness
itself, and of the shadow of death
without any order and where the light is
as darkness.
Y'all put a one in the chat with if
you're if you are following me so far,
put a one in the chat if you understand
what we have just laid out so far.
Because what we have just laid out so
far, beloved, is one of the most
mindblowing things that I've come to see
in the scriptures as I pondered on this
for this message.
I I don't know if you are ready. I don't
know if you if you maybe be you might be
deceived by my voice as I'm struggling
not to cough. And so I'm speaking in a
very low monotone way. I don't know if
you're if you're thinking, "Oh, well,
the good part hasn't come yet." The good
part has already come. And maybe you
haven't seen it. And so
I I need to paint this for you so that
you understand, beloved, that that in
that tomb
is utter darkness. In that tomb is utter
chaos. in that tomb is utter emptiness.
It is it is almost as if
something is about to happen in that
tomb
that will reveal
the amazing
goodness of God. That tomb becomes
ground zero for darkness, for chaos, for
voidness, for for emptiness. It is the
lowest that man could go in killing the
creator of the world. And now I want you
to see something. We have painted the
picture. Now I want you to come with me
to John chap 20 verse 1 and two. The
Bible says now on the first day of the
week Mary Magdalene came early to the
tomb while it was still dark. While it
was still dark. It was the first day of
the week.
while it was still dark
and saw the stone
had been taken away from the tomb. So
she ran and went to Simon Peter and the
other disciples with whom Jesus the one
whom Jesus loved and said unto them,
"They have taken the Lord out of the
tomb and we do not know where they have
laid him.
>> [clears throat]
>> You understand that it is at this point,
at this moment
that Jesus
is about to demonstrate his power.
But there may be something that you all
did not that we all may not have seen or
recognized before
because it is on the first day of the
week
that Jesus
who is the light
of the world
came forth
in a place
that was utter darkness that symbolized
utter darkness,
emptiness
in Genesis chapter 1
verse 1-5 the Bible says in the
beginning God created the heaven and the
earth and the earth was without form and
void and darkness was upon the face of
the deep.
If we go back to creation, the first
creation, by the way, the title of this
message is the second creation. If we go
back to creation, the first the place
that begins the creative power of God is
a place of utter darkness.
And it is in this utter darkness that
the Bible says in Genesis 1:3, "Then God
said, let there be light and there was
light." Remember you guys, this is on
the first day in in in in in 2
Corinthians chapter 4:6, the Bible says,
"For it is God who commanded the light
to shine out of darkness,
who has shown in our hearts to give the
light of the knowledge of the glory of
God in the face of Jesus Christ." Listen
y'all. I want you to imagine the tomb of
Jesus is a parallel to Genesis 1 where
Jesus the light is going to shine forth
in a place of utter darkness. The Bible
says in John 1 verse 4 and 5, in him was
the life and the life was the light of
men. The light shone in the darkness and
the darkness did not comprehend it. In
other words, beloved, I want you to
think of it in this sense. This is the
beginning of the creation of God.
This is why Revelation 3:14 calls Jesus
the beginning of the creation of God.
Not only in the creation account back
there in Genesis. But in essence,
beloved, what we are seeing
is that there was a second creation
account and it begins in a place where
which represents utter darkness, void,
emptiness, chaos.
As the world put their their savior to
death,
Jesus the light of the world comes
forth, shines forth in a place that is
utter darkness. See that tomb, that
little tomb as a parallel to the entire
world being in darkness. Because you
understand beloved, for Jesus to be dead
is for the entire world to be dead.
And so and so a new creation began in
the tomb.
And what I need you to understand
beloved is that no matter what your
darkest moments is, no matter what your
dark darkest moment is, no matter how
dark you think you are in a place where
light cannot penetrate, I need you to
understand and God need you to
understand that when light came forth in
that tomb because Jesus is the light, he
was demonstrating his power to penetrate
the deepest darknesses
of your life.
Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes. Not only,
beloved, not only did Jesus begin a new
creation, not only was a new creation
begun at the tomb, but I need you to
understand, beloved, that what we're
going to see in the early accounts of
the books of the of the book of Acts and
the Gospels
after the death of Christ is that there
is literally a recreation happening
underneath our noses. And we may not
have seen it. You see in Acts 2:1-3, the
Bible tells us that when the day of
Pentecost was fully come, they were all
with one accord in one place. And
suddenly there came a sound from heaven
as a rushing mighty wind, and it filled
all the house where they were sitting.
And there appeared unto them cloven
tongues like as a fire, and it sat upon
them. What I want you to understand,
beloved, is that here we have the Holy
Spirit descending and as it were
hovering.
I don't know. I don't know. [cough]
I [clears throat] don't know if y'all if
y'all understanding
what I am talking about right now.
The Holy Spirit is hovering
over the disciples. And you may say,
"Wait a minute, pastor. I I I I think I
remember you just read a little bit
earlier that just as that that in the
creation account, the spirit of God
hovering over the face of the waters.
Oh, pastor, what are you trying to tell
me? Are you trying to tell me?
Are you trying to tell me that that
through the the death and burial and
resurrection of Christ that there was a
new creation account happening?
Are you trying to tell me that just as
as as light, God said, "Let there be
light," where there was a place of pure
utter darkness and chaos, that when
Jesus came forth as the light of the
world in that tomb, that that is
paralleling? Are you trying to tell me
that when the spirit of God hovered over
the face of the earth, that this is
parallel to the Holy Spirit hovering
over the disciples?
Hold on, y'all. Hold on. Genesis 1 verse
6. And God said, "Let there be a
firmament in the midst of the waters,
and let it divide the waters from the
waters." And God made the firmament, and
divided the waters which were under the
firmament from the waters which were
above the firmament. And it was so. And
God called the firmament heaven. And I
want you to pause here for a second
because what I need you to understand,
beloved, is that when God called the
firmament heaven, he was creating the
atmosphere that would be necessary for
man to live. I don't know if y'all
caught that. He was creating the
atmosphere necessary so that man could
live, meaning man could breathe. And
what I need you to understand, beloved,
is that in this new creation account,
God is creating a spiritual world, as it
were,
where the where the spiritual man now
has access to breath.
You remember that God breathed the
ruach, the breath of life into Adam and
he became a living soul. Beloved, what
God is doing as he sends the Holy Spirit
on the day of Pentecost is he's
providing the breath. Y'all put a five
in the chat if you're following me. He's
providing the breath
that will be necessary. Remember how in
the creation account, man is not created
until the sixth day. So everything that
God is doing before that is he is
creating the atmosphere and the
environment and all the things necessary
for man to be able to survive. I need
y'all to catch me here. Man can't
survive without light. Man can't survive
without oxygen, without breath, without
air. And so what God is doing, beloved,
in this in this second creation account
where light comes forth out of a place
that represents utter darkness and chaos
and and emptiness and and and that light
comes forth and then that spirit comes
down and hovers on the on on the face of
the earth, hovering over the disciples,
providing that atmosphere
of the Holy Spirit, the breath that
would be necessary for man to live in
the spiritual realm.
The Bible tells us that on day three,
God said, "Let the earth bring forth
grass and herb yielding seed and the
fruit yielding tree after his kind,
whose seed is in itself." And it was so.
And the earth brought forth grass and
the herb yielding seed after his kind
yielding and and the tree yielding fruit
whose seed is in itself after his kind.
And God saw that it was good. And the
evening and the morning were the third
day. What I need y'all to understand is
that just as the fruits, the first
fruits began to come up out of the
ground on the third day, so beloved,
Jesus's resurrection, as the first
fruits coming up out of the ground on
the third day is a type of, listen to
me, it is a type of God preparing the
very food that we would need in order to
survive. You can't live without food.
And Jesus coming forth out of the ground
as the first fruits is the very bread of
life that we need.
In other words, beloved, in this
spiritual creation, those who are
eating, remember, it is on this day that
God brings forth everything that is to
be that that is to be eaten by mankind,
meaning the tree of life, the tree of
life that bore the fruit of life. And so
what I want you to understand, beloved,
is that through Jesus's death, burial,
and resurrection, he's created a second
a second tree of life, if you will,
which bears nine manner of fruit. The
fruit of the spirit is love, joy, peace,
longsuffering, gentleness, goodness,
faith, meekness, temperance. This is the
tree of life. This is the fruit
of life.
And and those who desire to live
in the spiritual creation that God has
made must have access to that tree of
life. Must eat of that tree of life.
Must eat of love and joy and peace and
longsuffering and gentleness. So what
God is doing beloved in essence is he is
creating a second creation through his
death there in the book of Matthew
chapter 27 and 28. Acts chapter 1 and
two. What we're watching unfold is a
second creation where light comes forth
from darkness where where where uh uh
where where the spirit hovers on the
face of the deep a and the disciples are
are are given the the breath of God if
you will that the first fruits come out
of the ground which is providing the
same thing that happened back there on
day three is providing the food
necessary that will be necessary for man
to live.
I need you to understand that on day
four, the Bible says, "And God said, let
there be the light. Let there be lights
in the firmament of the heavens to
divide the day from the night. Let them
be for signs and for seasons and for
days and for years. And let them be for
lights in the firmament of the heavens
to give light upon the earth." And it
was so. And God made the two great
lights, the greater light to rule the
day, and the lesser light to rule the
night. What I want y'all to understand,
beloved, is that the son of
righteousness, Malachi chapter 4:2, but
unto you that fear my name shall the son
su n of righteousness arise with healing
in his wings. What I need you to
understand, beloved, is that this son of
righteousness is a representation of
Jesus Christ as our high priest risen to
the heavens
interceding on our behalf.
I am I am telling you
it is as if Jesus was making a new
creation preparing for a people that he
would create in his image.
Light comes out of darkness. The spirit
of God hovers over his people. The first
fruits rising up out of the ground and
providing the very bread of life. the
very fruit, the very tree of life that
man would need in order to survive.
And then the son of righteousness
standing in the heavenly sanctuary on
our behalf, interceding on our behalf.
Wherefore in all things it behooved him
to be made like unto his brethren, that
he might be a merciful and faithful high
priest, the son of righteousness, in
things pertaining to God, to
[clears throat] make reconciliation for
the sins of his people.
Are y'all following this? Are y'all
catching what I'm saying here?
And beloved, just as on day five, the
Bible tells us that God begins to fill
the sea with fish, I need you to
understand, beloved, I need you to
understand that that when on the day of
Pentecost,
when 3,000 fish
are caught in the net,
when 3,000 souls are baptized, and you
understand what baptized means, right?
you you are in water and you are drawn
out of water. When the Bible says,
beloved, when Jesus said, "Follow me and
I will make you fishers of men." I need
you to understand, beloved, that in this
recreation account,
in this recreation account, God is not
only providing light from the darkness.
He is not only providing the oxygen
we're going to need to live. He's not
only providing the son of righteousness
only providing the fruit that we're
going to need to maintain life.
He he then says, "I'm going to multiply
and multiply and multiply."
Man, let me tell you beloved,
God
God is creating
God has created a new creation
which is designed and fitted
for the man who has been born again in
Jesus Christ.
This is why the Bible says in 2
Corinthians 5:17, "If any man be in
Christ, he's a new creature. Old things
are passed away. Behold, all things are
become new.
Y'all put a one in the chat if you're
following what I'm saying right now. In
in in Genesis chapter 1 verse 28, the
Bible says, "And God blessed them, and
God said unto them, listen."
So after God after God creates man in
his image,
which is exactly what happens on the day
of Pentecost when that pouring out of
the spirit represented
new creations in Christ Jesus. See this
see this scene
of creation happening again a second
time. It's as if God was like, "Listen,
all those who parttook who partake of
the first creation are going to die if
something doesn't happen. So, we're
going to we're going to do another
creation,
and it's going to be through Jesus
Christ, my son."
and and all who partake of this creation
willingly will escape the destruction
of that creation back there in the
beginning. In other words, all who are
part of the natural creation and who
only live for natural fruit and who only
live for natural air and who only
appreciate the natural son of
righteousness and who only appreciate
the natural light. All who only live in
the natural world [cough]
will not be able to experience the
blessings of the spiritual creation.
There is a second creation you guys. And
how many of us are living in that second
creation? How many of us are breathing
in that oxygen of the second creation?
Are living under the rays of the sun of
that second creation? Are eating the
food and the fruit of that second
creation. How many of us
[snorts]
while claiming to serve Jesus
are really only breathing in the oxygen
of this world,
the sunshine of this world.
I need you to understand, beloved, this
is why this is why when Jesus creates
man in his image, in this second
creation, remember Genesis 1:26 in the
first creation, God said, "Let us make
man in our image, after our likeness,
and let them have dominion over the fish
of the sea, and over the fowl of the
air, and over the cattle, and over all
the earth, and over every creeping thing
that creepeth upon the earth." In the
second creation, Jesus says the same
thing,
but now it's spiritual.
A and the command he gives,
the command he gives is to be fruitful.
Be fruitful
and multiply.
Beloved, that that is that is that is
the pure message of Christianity. Be
fruitful. Reflect me and multiply. Go
out and and and get more fish. Go out
and produce more like yourself.
Yeah. Now, now I want you to understand
beloved that what what is happening here
is that this is the gospel commission.
When Jesus says, "Go ye therefore and
teach all nations, baptizing them in the
name of the Father and of the Son and of
the Holy Ghost, teaching them to observe
all that I command you." What is
happening here is Jesus is saying,
"Listen y'all, you all who live in the
in the spiritual realm that I have
created, go out and reproduce. Bear
fruit and reproduce.
Bring other people into this creation.
That's what he's saying. Bring other
people into this reality.
I need you to stop and think carefully
about this you all
because [snorts] God is doing something
absolutely mindblowing in this story.
He's saying, "I want you to go out
and I want you to reflect my character.
And then I want you to be fruitful and
multiply. And watch this. I want you to
subdue
the earth.
I want you to subdue
the earth. In fact, I'm giving you
dominion. [clears throat]
[snorts] I'm giving you dominion over
everything. Now, watch this. Before I
get into this, I need you to see,
beloved, that according to second Peter
chapter 1:3, the Bible says, "According
as his divine power has given unto us
all things that pertain unto life and
godliness." I'mma pause right there.
What am I trying to say? What I'm trying
to say, beloved, is just as in the first
creation, God provided light and and
water and air and fruit, uh food and and
everything necessary for man to live in
the real world. So in the second
creation, he has provided everything
necessary for us to survive.
We do not need to go out there and find
our own air. We [snorts] do not need to
go and till the ground to bear fruit.
It's already there for us. Everything
that we need is already there for us. He
has provided it in the new creation.
Are y'all following me?
So, so the light of the gospel, the
breath of the spirit, the water of life,
the fruit of the spirit, the son of
righteousness, he said, "I've given you
all of this. Now, what I want you to do
is I want you to go I want you to to to
to I'm giving you dominion over the fish
of the sea and over the beasts of the
field.
I need y'all to understand this guys
because in a spiritual context what
Jesus is saying is listen I want you to
go out there and be a fisher of men but
I need you to also understand that I've
given you dominion over the beasts
of the field.
You will you will remember
you [snorts] will remember that that in
Genesis chapter 3 the Bible talks about
this beast that was more subtle. Let's
read in Genesis 3 verse one. The Bible
says now the serpent was more subtle
than any beast of the field which the
Lord God had made. You remember this
story, right? The the the serpent is a
beast. We know that behind the serpent
was Satan.
>> [snorts]
>> In this in that old creation, the beast
got dominion over man. In the new
creation, God says, "I have given you
dominion over the beast." And I want you
to understand that in two ways. First of
all, yes, he's given us dominion over
the beastly nature that that we once
had. But but there's something else I
need you to understand, beloved. That
that there are beasts of this earth
Understand Revelation 12:12. Therefore,
rejoice ye heavens and ye that dwell in
them. Woe unto the inhabitants of the
earth and of the sea. For the devil is
come down unto you having great wrath
because he knows he has a but a short
time. And the text goes on to call him
that old serpent. That dragon, the old
serpent.
In Daniel chapter 7, uh the Bible speaks
about four beasts, a lion, a bear, a
leopard, and a dragon. and and God is in
essence telling us, "Beloved, listen.
In Revelation [clears throat] 13:11,
this beast is going to seek to destroy
God's people. But I need you to know
that I have given you dominion over the
beasts."
Revelation 13:11, I saw another beast
coming up out of the out of the earth.
He had horns like a lamb and spake like
a dragon. God is saying despite all the
beasts that are going to come and attack
you prophetically speaking at the end of
time I need you to understand one thing.
Never let the beast in here or the
beasts out there cause you to doubt the
word of God. Because what the beast will
do, what the devil is simply seeking to
do, just like he did with Adam and Eve
in the garden, is he's trying to get you
to say, "Has God really said?"
He's trying to get you to doubt
the word of God. He's trying to get you
to doubt the promises of God. He's
trying to get you to to doubt the
goodness of God. That's what he wants.
And the reason that he wants to do that,
beloved, is so that when God comes back
for this garden, when God comes back,
understand what I'm saying, y'all. When
God comes back, he wants you,
the devil wants you to be ashamed and
naked and afraid just like in the first
creation account.
So God's mission for his church, God's
mission for his people in this second
creation is to be fruitful and populate
this earth.
What earth you talking about, God? This
earth? No, no, no, no. I'm talking about
the spiritual realm, the spiritual
creation that I have created, beginning
with Jesus in the darkest place that
this planet has ever seen. The tomb, the
tomb of of Jesus himself, that is the
darkest creation, the second creation
account began there.
So now God is saying to his people,
populate
this world,
populate this creation,
populate this realm.
So for those of us living in the second
creation, now you understand what I mean
when I say the second creation. We now
understand. Oh, so just as God gave Adam
and Eve that task to be fruitful and
multiply and to keep
what God had already provided.
Now we understand ah our me our mission
as God's [snorts] people is is to is to
be about our father's business is to
populate this realm that's why the three
angels messages is gone to every nation
kindred tongue and people inviting them
into this garden inviting them into this
creation
and beloved I need you to understand
something so powerful here because
[sighs]
you do not need to doubt God or his
word. [snorts]
If you look back at 2025, you might say
2025 was not my year. I can say 2025
is a is a year that I cannot wait to
forget.
You know, this this new year was not a
happy new year for me. this this new
year, this Christmas, I I'm remembering
last year, this very time, me looking in
my brother's eyes and telling him,
"Sean, you're going to be okay. You're
you're going to,
we will spend another Christmas
together. God is going to work this
thing out."
And in a few days, my brother was gone.
Yeah. 2025 is a year that I would like
to forget.
And yet, despite all of that, beloved,
despite all of that, when when the devil
points and says, "See, where was God
here? When where was God there?" You
need to understand that he's doing he's
attempting to do just like he did with
Adam and Eve in the garden to cause
doubt in God's word, beloved. and do not
let it happen because God is love. And
I'm telling you, listen to me. Listen to
me.
You remember in the in the it's such a
powerful reheversal in the garden. You
remember in the garden when Adam and Eve
sinned, God looking for them
and he finds them naked.
He finds them in a condition that is
destined for death.
But in the second creation,
[snorts]
in the second creation,
Mary goes looking for Jesus.
Wow.
And what she finds is life.
What she finds is life.
What a reversal.
God looking for man in the garden and he
finds him hiding in sin and death. Mary
going to the to the place where Jesus is
crucified that the the garden which was
his tomb and what she finds is life.
[clears throat]
And this is what God is trying to tell
us beloved.
Despite all the despite the darknesses
of the tombs that we face, despite the
the the the utter emptiness and void and
chaos, how could this happen? This is
chaos. It doesn't make sense. It does
not make sense. Chaos is not supposed to
make sense. But that God can bring light
in chaos.
Beloved, wow. God
becomes the very strength that we need
in our most chaotic times.
And so listen,
when Jesus returns,
just as God came to the garden and Adam
and Eve were afraid and hid themselves,
beloved, at the very end of time, Jesus
is coming again.
And there will be people who cry out,
"Hide us from the wrath of the lamb and
from him that siteth on the throne." But
God does not want anybody crying that
out.
You see beloved, when Jesus comes again,
he's coming again to put the end touches
on what he said in the first creation,
which was
the seed will bruise the head of the
serpent.
When he comes again the second time in
the second creation account, when he
comes back to the garden the second
time, it is to crush the head of the
serpent. He's not out to crush our
heads. He's not out to crush your head.
But beloved, if you get caught up with
the enemy,
you will stand before God just like Adam
and Eve did in that garden,
and you're not going to be able to say,
"She made me do it. He made me do it.
The devil made me do it.
And there will be no plan of salvation
for those
who reject the plan God has already laid
out for them.
Beloved, we want to be of that class
which is spoken of in Revelation 22:14.
Blessed are they that they are they that
do his commandments that they may have
right to the tree of life and may enter
in through the gates into the city.
Remember when Adam and Eve sin,
a flaming sword is put around the tree
of life and they are put out of the
city. Isn't it beautiful that God
actually said, "We're going to do this
again. We're going to recreate
We're going to recreate.
And all who who all who will
[snorts] are invited to come into this
new creation.
They're invited to come into this world
where the source of light is Jesus.
Where the source of food is Jesus,
where the source of air is the Holy
Spirit,
where the source of light is Jesus,
where I will give you dominion over the
fish of the sea and over the over the
beasts of the earth so that you can so
you can win the fish of the sea and even
win the beasts of the earth. even win
those with that nature that is just so
harsh. I'm going to give you dominion.
The beasts of the earth will not have
dominion over you. You will be made in
my image and in my likeness. I'm going
to seal you. And when the enemy comes
to say, "Yeah, has God said and you
stand firm and stand strong and stand
true and refuse to eat from his tree,
but only eat from the fruits of the
righteousness of Christ."
When Jesus comes back to his garden, his
creation, his people,
he will say,
"Here is access
to the tree of life.
Eat and live forever.
Eat and live forever."
And as for the devil, that old serpent,
his head will be bruised
and all who follow him will be bruised,
destroyed,
finished.
Beloved, as we enter into this new year,
I want you to keep this message
[snorts] and keep this understanding
in the forefront of your mind.
What world am I living in?
Help me to breathe the atmosphere of
heaven. Help me to eat the food of
heaven.
Help me to to to to get the raise from
the son of righteousness of heaven.
Help me to live in this new creation and
know that everything that pertainth to
godliness and life, God has already
provided it in this in this new
creation.
and help me to be fruitful and multiply
and exercise dominion over the fish of
the sea and over the beasts of the
earth. Help me to be made and sealed in
the image of God so that
so that when he comes again
to take us to heaven, we can spend that
eternal
sabotismos with him where from one new
moon to another and from one Sabbath to
another all flesh will come before him
and worship. ship having access to the
tree of life. It if it is your desire,
if it is your desire, pastor, I've
I never understood
that there was another creation that I'm
called to live in.
I've been trying to follow Jesus, but
living in the real world. I haven't been
breathing
the atmosphere of heaven. I haven't been
absorbing
the rays of the sun of righteousness.
You know how they tell you every day you
need to go out and make sure you get the
sun. You need to go out, guys, and make
sure you get the sun. Are you getting
the rays of the sun?
Are you getting the air of the spirit?
Are you getting the water of life? Are
you getting the fruit of the spirit? Are
you getting these things that are so
necessary for your spiritual growth and
strength?
You're saying today, Lord, help me to
live
in this in this realm of the unseen.
Help me to live in this world that is
only seen and experienced by faith. I I
call it the faith world. Help me to live
in the faith world, Lord.
that is your desire, put that one in the
chat and I'm going to pray.
Heavenly Father,
Lord, your people
are beginning a new year.
Many of us are tired from this past
year.
Many of us, this past year has been
unbelievable,
unbelievably difficult,
unbelievably challenging.
And Lord, the enemy comes and seeks to
to to plant fears and doubts.
And Lord, [snorts] now we understand
why.
Because you have created a world in
which you've invited us to live. And the
enemy is seeking to have us eat from the
tree of the knowledge of good and evil
that we may be excluded from living in
this world.
Please Lord, help us not to make the
first mistakes, make the mistakes of our
first parents,
but Lord, help us to live
according to your word.
Help us to live by faith.
Help us to live in this faith world,
Lord.
And Lord, when you come again, may we
not run away naked and ashamed,
but Lord, may we greet you
in full confidence
because of the love that you have for
us.
May we greet you in peace.
And Lord, we pray that we might be ready
to enter that heavenly place with you,
eat from the tree of life, and live
forever with you.
Forgive us, Lord, for our sins. Forgive
us, Lord, for living in the real world
while excluding the faith world.
Please Lord
grant us your spirit,
your air,
your presence, your food,
your water,
your light.
Grant it all to us, Lord, that we may
live and reflect your glory and
goodness. Grant us Lord dominion to
subdue and to populate this earth.
This we pray in the precious and holy
name of Jesus. Amen. And amen.
We're going to invite you all to uh join
us for our after uh our afterlow. We're
going to put the link um to Mighty
Networks uh in the chat. And so for
those of you that would like to to join
us um where we will talk about the
sermon, the Sabbath school, and just
fellowship, we welcome you. And um
um we are uh looking looking forward to
fellowshipping with you. Um I'm going to
again just uh wait for that link to go
up before we sign off. And again, I'm
going to say, may God bless you, may God
keep you, uh, and may God allow this
truth to just marinate in your souls,
and may it guide the way that you live
and breathe and have your being from
this day forward. Again, God bless you
and um, happy Sabbath. See you next
week.
>> Thank you for joining us today. If this
is your first time worshiping with us,
please check out our website at
livingmana.urch.
We are not just here for Sabbath
service. We [music] have weekly
programming too that covers mental
health, physical health, weekly prayer
service, financial health, and proving
the existence of God. It is our desire
that our programming will continue to
bless you. Please continue to pray for
us as we fulfill God's mission to go
into all the world with the gospel of
Jesus Christ.